

SUMMARY

Experienced (15+ years) technology practitioner with a demonstrated history of eminence in the consulting industry. Skilled in designing, building & implementing **technology solutions** in enterprise landscape. Strong technology professional with majors in **Computer** Sciences and Engg.

Ashutosh Pathak Principal Architect, McKinsey & Co.







ashutosh.pathak.in@gmail.com in



SKILLS

Cloud Product Implementn.

System Architecture

Data Integrations

Security

Good Engineering Practices

Problem Solving

People Development

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS, SAP, Kafka, APIs, Java, Middleware platforms

EDUCATION

2004 - 2008

B.Tech, Computer Science National Institute of Tech. India (Grade – 8.6)

EXPERIENCE

SuccessConnect 2017 Co-Speaker

Principal Architect

McKinsey & Company, Jun 2019 - Current

Led a high performing engineering team of 40+ members across multiple products. Designed scalable, resilient, and secure architectures for a hybrid enterprise landscape for people systems, with a strong focus on HRIS and downstream consumer systems integrations. Led platform modernization efforts and adoption of emerging technologies. Initiatives to enhance engineering productivity, including AWS cloud migration, adoption of CI/CD pipelines, automation testing frameworks, and containerization technologies. Managed budgetary planning and resource allocations for engineering projects. Led the recruitment and professional development of engineering talent. Skilled in technology selection, stakeholder management, vendor management.

Technology Consulting Manager Deloitte Consulting, Jan 2016 - Jun 2019

Managed & delivered 6+ Cloud product implementations with heavy focus on industry leading practices, technology innovations, end user experience & personalization. Leveraged design thinking, RPA, continuous improvement & sustainment models. Participated in the bid & proposals & client Orals during pursuits. Assisted with RFIs/ RFPs. Extensive experience with technology sustenance & support.

Software Engineering Lead Accenture, June 2008 – Jan 2016

Led and delivered application development and system integration projects in the HR domain. Managed complex system landscapes and architectures, including clusters, load balancers, middleware, frontend, and backend layers. Possess comprehensive experience in the web technology stack, including Java/J2EE, JavaScript, HTML, RESTful/SOAP APIs, SAML/SSO, Oracle PL SQL, and Business Intelligence reporting.